Serge Diaghilev/Serge Lifar Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
- I. Printed Music Material, 1750-1950 (Box 1-67)
  - A. General (Box 1-65)
    - Musorgskiĭ, Modest Petrovich
      - La foire de Sorotchintsi: Introduction. Petrograd: W. Bessel, 1909., Arranged by C. Tchernov for piano, four hands; score; 11 p.; Plate no. 5402.; Published 1909/1921 (Box-folder 38/3)
      - La foire de Sorotchintsi: Introduction. Petrograd: W. Bessel, 1909., Arranged by C. Tchernov for solo piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. 6633.; Published 1909/1921 (Box-folder 38/4)
      - La foire de Sorotchintsi: Rêverie du jeune villageois. [=Dumka parobka.] Petrograd: W. Bessel, 1909. See also: La foire de Sorotchintsi: Chanson du jeune villageois, Box 37, Folder 19, Arranged for voice and piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. 5412.; Published 1909/1921; Language note: French; Language note: English; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 38/5)
      - La foire de Sorotchintsi: Scène du compère et de Tchérévik. Leipzig: W. Bessel, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 11 p.; Plate no. 7155.; Language note: French; Language note: German; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 38/6)
      - Iisus Navin. [=Joshua, or Jesus Navinus.] St. Petersburg: V. Bessel', 1883., Vocal soloists (AB), chorus, piano; piano-vocal score (17 p.), vocal parts for SATB; 17 p.; 2 p.; 2 p.; 3 p.; 2 p.; Plate no. 1521.; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 38/7)
      - Kallistrate. St. Petersburg: W. Bessel, 1908., Voice and piano; score; 11 p.; Plate no. 5948.; Language note: French; Language note: German; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 38/8)
      - Khovanshchina. St. Petersburg: V. Bessel', 1882., Piano-vocal score; 207 p.; Plate no. 1507 through 1518.; Contains numerous annotations in pencil and in ink, as well as manuscript emendations laid in.; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 38/9)
      - Khovanshchina: Entr'acte (to Act IV, Scene II). Petrograd: W. Bessel, 1910., Arranged by C. Tchernov for two pianos; score; 7 p.; Plate no. W.6635 B.; Published 1910/1913 (Box-folder 38/10)
      - Khovanshchina [S.l.]: [s.n.], n.d., Chorus parts for soprano; 101 p.; 8 pages contain manuscript emendations in ink, laid in or affixed. Items may also contain performance indications in pencil. (Box-folder 38/11)
      - Khovanshchina [S.l.]: [s.n.], n.d., Chorus parts for alto; 83 p.; Items may also contain performance indications in pencil. (Box-folder 38/12)
      - Khovanshchina [S.l.]: [s.n.], n.d., Chorus parts for tenor; 113 p.; Items may also con-tain performance indications in pencil. (Box-folder 38/13)
      - Khovanshchina [S.l.]: [s.n.], n.d., Chorus parts for bass; 112 p.; Items may also con-tain performance indications in pencil. (Box-folder 38/14)
      - Le mariage. [=Zhenit'ba; The marriage.] St. Petersburg: W. Bessel, 1911., Piano-vocal score; 64 p.; Plate no. 5967.; Language note: French; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 39/1)
      - Une nuit sur le mont chauve. [=Night on Bald Mountain.] Petrograd: W. Bessel, 1920., Arranged by N. Artzibouchev for piano, four hands; score; 35 p.; Plate no. 1539. (Box-folder 39/2)
      - Oedipe: Choeur. [=Oedipus in Athens: Chorus]. St. Petersburg: W. Bessel, 1909., Piano-vocal score; 13 p.; Plate no. 6697.; Language note: French; Language note: German (Box-folder 39/3)
      - L'orgueil. [=Spies'; Pride.] St. Petersburg: W. Bessel, 1908., Voice and piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. 5941.; Language note: French; Language note: German; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 39/4)
      - La peine. [=Ne bozhiim gromom gore udarilo.] St. Petersburg: W. Bessel, 1908., Voice and piano; 5 p.; Plate no. 5939. (Box-folder 39/5)
      - La pie. [=Strekotun'ia bieloboka; The magpie.] St. Petersburg: W. Bessel, 1908., Voice and piano; score; 9 p.; Plate no. 5931.; Language note: French; Language note: German; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 39/6)
      - Pirouchka. [=The feast.] Leipzig: M.P. Belaïeff, 1898., Voice and piano; score; 3 p.; Plate no. 1157 1163.; Language note: French; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 39/7)
      - Sorochinskaia iarmarka See also: La foire de Sorotchintsi
      - Sorochinskaia iarmarka: Komicheskiia stseny. [=Sorochintsy fair: Burlesque (Act II).] St. Petersburg: V. Bessel', n.d., Piano-vocal score; 77 p.; Plate no. 7050.; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 39/8)
      - Sorochinskaia iarmarka: Vstuplenie i iarmarochkaia stsena. [=Sorochintsy fair: Introduction and fair scene (Act I).] St. Petersburg: V. Bessel', n.d., Piano-vocal score; 41 p.; Plate no. 7145.; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 39/9)
      - Sur le Dnièpr. [=Na Dnieprie; On the Dniepr.] St. Petersburg: W. Bessel, 1908., Voice and piano; score; 9 p.; Plate no. 5946.; Language note: French; Language note: German; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 39/10)
      - Tableaux d'une exposition. [=Pictures at an exhibition.] Paris: W. Bessel, n.d., Solo piano; score; 31 p.; Plate no. 1560.; Contains annotations in pencil and in ink. (Box-folder 39/11)
      - Trouble. [=Razsievaetsia, razstupaetsia.] St. Petersburg: W. Bessel, 1908., Voice and piano; score; 3 p.; Plate no. 5943.; Language note: French; Language note: German; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 39/12)
      - [Works for voice and piano.] See: I.B. Collections, Box 4 (S/65), p. 69-70
    - Nabokov, Nicolas
      - Le Coeur de Don Quichotte. [=Serdtse Don Kikhota.] Berlin: Édition russe de musique, n.d., Solo piano; score; 14 p.; Plate no. R.M.V.550. (Box-folder 39/13)
      - Ode. [=Oda.] Paris: M. Senart, n.d., Vocal soloists (SB), mixed chorus (SATB), orchestra; piano-vocal score; 1 p.; Plate no. E.M.S.7598.; Contains holograph dedication to Diaghilev from the composer, dated 1928 Jun 6.; Language note: French; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 39/14)
      - Shot stories. Paris: Rouart, n.d., Solo piano; score; 11 p.; Also published Paris: Lerolle, n.d.; Plate no. R.L.11616 & Cie. (Box-folder 39/15)
    - Nascimbene, Mario
      - Pigmalione. Milan: Mario Nascimbene, 1946., Reduction for solo piano; score; 62 p.; Laid in: photoreproduced typescript of the ballet's synopsis, 9 p., in Italian. (Box-folder 39/16)
    - Neustedt, C.
      - Le rêve du prisonnier See: I.B. Collections, Box 3 (S/64), p. 68-69
    - Ocki-Albi, Georges N.
      - Palais du crystal See: I.B. Collections, Box 2 (S/63), p. 67-68.
      - Petite conversation See: I.B. Collections, Box 3 (S/64), p. 68-69
    - Offenbach, Jacques
      - Apothicaire et perruquier. Paris: Heugel, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 38 p.; Plate no. H.5284.; Language note: French (Box-folder 39/17)
      - La bonne d'enfant. Paris: Heugel, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 54 p.; Plate no. H.1976.; Language note: French (Box-folder 39/18)
      - Les contes d'Hoffmann: selections. Moscow: A. Gutheil, n.d., Arranged for solo piano; score; 87 p.; Plate no. A.7585 G.; Bound with: Chopin, Frédéric.Walzer [Sämmtliche Pianoforte-Werke: Walzer]. Edited by H. Scholtz. Solo piano; score. Leipzig: C.F. Peters, n.d., 79 p. Plate no. 8946. (Box-folder S/44)
      - Les contes d'Hoffmann: O belle nuit (Barcarolle). Paris: A. Choudens, n.d., Arranged by F. Spindler for solo piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. A.C.5223. (Box-folder 39/19)
      - Une demoiselle en loterie. Paris: Heugel, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 64 p.; Plate no. H.2092.; Language note: French (Box-folder 39/20)
      - Le financier et le savetier. Paris: Heugel, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 56 p.; Plate no. H.et Cie.1932.; Language note: French (Box-folder 40/1)
      - Le mariage aux lanternes. Paris: Heugel, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 72 p.; Plate no. H.2147.; Language note: French (Box-folder 40/2)
      - Monsieur et Madame Denis. Paris: Heugel, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 100 p.; Plate no. H.4663.; Language note: French (Box-folder 40/3)
      - Prekrasnaia Elena. [=La belle Hélène See: I.B. Collections, Box 2 (S/63), p. 67-68.
      - Valse chaloupée See: I.B. Collections, Box 3 (S/64), p. 68-69.
    - O'Hara, Geoffrey
      - K-K-K-Katy. Constantinople: J. d'Andria, n.d., Voice and piano; score; 3 p.; Plate no. 336.; Language note: English (Box-folder 40/4)
    - Oréfiche, Armando
      - Puchunguita. Paris: Éditions espagnoles J. Garzón, n.d., Small orchestra; parts for: piano/conductor's score, vn (2 p. each); vc/tbn-cb, sax I (alto)-sax III (alto), tpt, banjo/guitar/vn II-sax II (tenor) (1 p. each); perc (2 p.).; Plate no. 1773.; parts for: piano/conductor's score containing vocal line indications in Spanish; On verso of each part: corresponding instrumental part for Cueva, Julio. Ajonjoli. Small orchestra; parts for: piano/conductor's score (containing vocal line indications in Spanish)(2 p.); vn, vc-cb, sax I (alto)-sax III (alto), tpt, banjo/ guitar-sax II (tenor), perc (1 p. each). Paris: Éditions espagnoles J. Garzón, n.d. Plate no. 1774. (Box-folder 40/5)
    - Paderewski, Ignace Jan
      - Menuet, op. 14, no. 1. Berlin: E. Bote & G. Bock, n.d., Solo piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. 13268.14588. (Box-folder 40/6)
    - Paër, Ferdinando
      - Il maestro di cappella. Milan: G. Ricordi, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 101 p.; Plate no. 99800.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder S/26)
    - Paisiello, Giovanni
      - Il barbiere di Siviglia. Milan: G. Ricordi, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 237 p.; Plate no. 46102.; Contains annotations on inside front cover page, in pencil; an autograph of Lifar, in pencil; an inscription in French, in pencil: "These annotations come from the hand of Serge de Diaghilev"; sparse annotations in pencil in the score itself.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder S/27)
      - Il mio ben quando verrà. Milan: G. Ricordi, n.d., Voice and piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. 51952.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 40/7)
      - La molinara: Mon coeur est sans jeunesse. [=Nel cor più non mi sento.] Milan: G. Ricordi, n.d., Arranged for voice and piano; score; 3 p.; Plate no. 113475.; Language note: French; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 40/8)
      - La molinara: Nel cor più non mi sento. Milan: G. Ricordi, n.d., Arranged for voice and piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. 16185.; p. 59 through 65 of the Antologia classica musicale; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 40/9)
      - La molinara: Ouverture und favorite Arien. Bonn: N. Simrock, n.d., Reduction for piano solo/voice and piano by C. G. Neefe; score; [12] p.; Plate no. 13.; incomplete: p. 1-12 only; Language note: German; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 40/10)
      - La molinara: Per marito vossignoria. Milan: G. Ricordi, n.d., Arranged for two voices and piano; score; 9 p.; Plate no. 110339.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 40/11)
      - Nina, oder Wahnsinn aus Liebe. Mannheim: I.M. Gotz, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 165 p.; Plate no. 308.; Language note: Italian; Language note: German (Box-folder S/29)
      - Nina, ossia la pazza per amore. Paris: Carli, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 161 p.; Plate no. 459.; Contains annotations in pencil.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder S/48)
      - I zingari infiera: Chi vuol la zingarella. Milan: G. Ricordi, n.d., Arranged for voice and piano; score; 4 p.; Plate no. 51950.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 40/12)
    - Paladilhe, Émile
      - Mandolinata See: I.B. Collections, Box 2 (S/63), p. 67-68.
    - Patáky, Hubert
      - Prometheus, op. 31. Berlin: Verlag alte und neue Kunst, 1927., Reduction for solo piano; score; 41 p.; Plate no. 71.; Laid in: photoreproduced publicity material, 1 p., in German. (Box-folder 40/13)
    - Pedrotti, Carlo
      - Tutti in maschera. Milan: G. Ricordi, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 242 p.; Plate no. 42058.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 40/14)
    - Pergolesi, Giovanni Battista
      - Livietta e Tracollo. Paris: M. Senart, 1914., Piano-vocal score; 92 p.; Plate no. M.S. & Cie.3312.; Contents: BOX: 40/15 Copy 1: contains annotations in pencil. BOX: 40/16 Copy 2 of the above.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 40/15-16)
      - Olimpiade. Milan: Associazione dei musicologi italiani, 1915., Piano-vocal score; 287 p.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 41/1)
      - Olimpiade: Se cerca, se dice l'amico dov'è. Milan: G. Ricordi, n.d., Arranged for voice and piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. 101917-18-45.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 41/2)
      - La serva padrona. Milan: G. Ricordi, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 59 p.; Plate no. 45390.; Hardcover copy; Language note: Italian (Box-folder S/31)
      - La serva padrona. Milan: G. Ricordi, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 59 p.; Plate no. 45390.; Contains annotations in pencil on index page and on p. 59; softcover copy.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 41/3)
      - La serva padrona: Stizzoso, mio stizzoso. Milan: G. Ricordi, n.d., Arranged for voice and piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. 51944.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 41/4)
      - Sonate [no.] 12. Milan: G. Ricordi, n.d., Violin and figured bass; parts for vn, vc; 30 p.; 33 p.; Plate no. 108152.; cello part arranged from the violin part by L.S. Giarda (Box-folder 41/5)
      - Sonata, D major. London: Schott & Co., n.d., Solo keyboard; score; 11 p.; Plate no. 26783.; Contains inscription on title page, in Russian, in ink. (Box-folder 41/6)
      - Tre giorni son che Nina. Milan: G. Ricordi, n.d., Voice and piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. 36235.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 41/7)
    - Pesse, Maurice
      - Sur un vieux thème russe. Paris: L. Philippo, 1928., Solo piano; score; 4 p.; Plate no. P.1433. (Box-folder 41/8)
    - Petrella, Errico
      - Il carnevale di Venezia. Milan: G. Ricordi, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 339 p.; Plate no. 108670.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 41/9)
    - Petrov, B.
      - Zhemchuzhiny russkoĭ narodnoĭ piesni: 100 velikorusskikh narodnykh piesen. [="Pearls" of old Russian folk song: 100 Russian folksongs.] St. Petersburg: IU.G. TSimmerman, 1902., Arranged for voice and piano; score; 61 p.; Plate no. Z.6374 a, b.; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 42/1)
    - Pinsuti, Ciro
      - El libro santo. Milan: G. Ricordi, n.d., Voice and piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. 49920.; Language note: Spanish; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 42/2)
    - Pirani, G.
      - Altalena See: I.B. Collections, Box 2 (S/63), p. 67-68.
    - Planquette, Robert
      - Les cloches de Corneville: Chanson des servantes See: I.B. Collections, Box 2 (S/63), p. 67-68.
    - Plevitskaia, Nadezhda V.
      - Moskovskaia troĭka. Moscow: S.IA. IAmbor, n.d., Voice and piano; score; 3 p.; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 42/3)
      - Zolotym kol'tsom skovali. Moscow: S.IA. IAmbor, n.d., Voice and piano; score; 3 p.; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 42/4)
    - Poldowski
      - Caledonian market. London: J. & W. Chester, 1923., Solo piano; score; 23 p.; Plate no. J.W.C.2111.; Contains holograph dedication to Diaghilev from the composer, on verso of cover page, in ink.; Composer also known by the name: Paul, Dean, Lady (Box-folder 42/5)
    - Poulenc, Francis
      - Sonate. London: J. & W. Chester, 1924., Clarinet and bassoon; score; 12 p.; Plate no. J.W.C.228. (Box-folder 42/6)
      - Sonate. London: J. & W. Chester, 1919., Two clarinets; score; 11 p.; Plate no. J.W.C.219. (Box-folder 42/7)
      - Sonate. London: J. & W. Chester, 1924., Horn, trumpet and trombone; parts; 4 p.; 4 p.; 4 p.; Plate no. J.W.C.229. (Box-folder 42/8)
    - Prisovskiĭ, V. A.
      - Serenada, op. 92. Moscow: L. Idzikovskiĭ, n.d., Solo piano; score; 3 p.; Plate no. L.2991 I. (Box-folder 42/9)
    - Prokof'ev, Sergeĭ Sergeevich
      - Liubov' k trem apel'sinam, op. 33. [=The Love for three oranges.] Moscow: A. Gutheil, 1922., Piano-vocal score; 252 p.; Plate no. A.10321 G.; Language note: French; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 42/10)
      - Skazka pro Shuta. [=Chout.] Moscow: A. Gutheil, n.d., Solo piano; score; 64 p.; Plate no. A.10308 G.; Laid in: holograph annotations by the composer in pencil; separately: copyist's score of the composer's published piano reduction, separated by act (Act I: 10 p.; Act 2: 15 p.; Act 3: 35 p.), and containing annotations in pencil. (Box-folder S/49)
      - Shut: Siuita iz baleta, op. 21b. [=Chout: Ballet suite.] Moscow: A. Gutheil, 1924., Miniature score; 156 p.; Plate no. A.G.10358. (Box-folder 42/11)
      - Stal'noĭ skok, op. 41. [=Le pas d'acier; The steel step.] Berlin: Édition russe de musique, 1928., Solo piano; score; 59 p.; Plate no. R.M.V.444. (Box-folder 42/12)
    - Puare, Mariia IAkovlevna
      - IA iekhala domoĭ. Moscow: A. Gutkheil', n.d., Voice and piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. A.8985 G. (Box-folder 42/13)
    - Puccini, Giacomo
      - Bogema. [=La Bohème.] St. Petersburg: A. Iogansen, 1899., Piano-vocal score; 103 p.; Plate no. 2474.; Language note: Italian; Language note: Russian (Box-folder S/50)
      - La bohème: O Mimì tu più non torni. Milan: G. Ricordi, 1896., Arranged for voice and piano; score; 4 p.; Plate no. 99351.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 42/14)
      - La bohème: Sì, mi chiamano Mimì. Constantinople: J. d'Andria, n.d., Arranged for voice and piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. 385.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 42/15)
      - La bohème: Votre main est glacée. Milan: G. Ricordi, 1898., Arranged for voice and piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. 101902.; Language note: French (Box-folder 42/16)
      - Madama Butterfly London: G. Ricordi, 1905., Arranged by C. Godfrey for solo piano; score; 19 p.; Plate no. 110877.; excerpts (Box-folder 43/1)
      - Tosca: Le ciel luisait d'étoiles (Act III). Milan: G. Ricordi, 1908., Arranged for voice and piano; score; 4 p.; Plate no. 112398.; Language note: French (Box-folder 43/2)
      - Tosca: D'art et d'amour, je vivais toute. (Prière de Tosca) (Act II). [S.l.]: [s.n.], n.d., Arranged for voice and piano; score; 5 p.; Language note: French; Possibly published in Constantinople by J. d'Andria (Box-folder 43/3)
    - Purcell, Henry
      - Ten pianoforte pieces. London: Novello, n.d., Solo piano; score; 30 p.; Plate no. 10066. (Box-folder 43/4)
      - Fourteen pieces. London: Novello, n.d., Arranged by A. Dolmetsch for violin and piano; violin part, piano score; 11 p.; 27 p.; Plate no. 9119. (Box-folder 43/5)
      - Purcell album. London: Schott, 1918., Arranged by H. Fryer for solo piano; score; 13 p.; Plate no. S. & Co.3649 through 3651. (Box-folder 43/6)
      - Allemande. Paris: M. Senart, n.d., Arranged by A. Sauvrezis for solo piano; score; 3 p.; Plate no. M.S. & Cie.1335. (Box-folder 43/7)
      - The Fairy Queen. London: Novello, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 164 p.; Plate no. 14056.; Language note: English (Box-folder 43/8)
      - Suite, C major. Paris: M. Senart, n.d., Solo piano; score; 9 p.; Plate no. M.S. & Cie 646, 647. (Box-folder 43/9)
      - Suite, D major. Paris: M. Senart, n.d., Solo piano; score; 4 p.; Plate no. M.S. & Cie 644. (Box-folder 43/10)
    - Rachmaninoff, Sergeĭ
      - Morceaux de fantaisie, op. 3, no. 2: Prélude. Moscow: A. Gutheil, n.d., Solo piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. A.6516 G.; 2 copies (Box-folder 43/11)
      - Morceaux de fantaisie, op. 3, no. 5: Sérénade. Moscow: A. Gutheil, n.d., Solo piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. A.6519 G. (Box-folder 43/12)
      - 24 Préludes. [from opp. 3, 23, 32.] Moscow: A. Gutheil, n.d., Solo piano; score; 108 p.; Plate no. A.6516 G., 8338 through 8347, 9612 through 9624. (Box-folder S/51)
    - Raimondi, Pietro
      - Il ventaglio. Naples: T. Cottrau, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 211 p.; Plate no. 17386, 1950, 1946, 1934, 17387 through 17390, 1982, 1989, 1938, 17391, 1979.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 43/13)
    - Rameau, Jean Philippe
      - Pièces de clavecin. Paris: A. Durand, n.d., Solo piano; score; 113 p.; Plate no. D. & F.5007.; Preface by C. Saint-Saëns. (Box-folder 43/14)
      - Symphonies des Indes galantes. [Les Indes galantes: selections.] Paris: Éditions musicales transatlantiques, 1937., Miniature score; 49 p.; Plate no. E.M.T.413. (Box-folder 43/15)
    - Ravel, Maurice
      - L'heure espagnole. Paris: A. Durand, 1908., Piano-vocal score; 114 p.; Plate no. D. & F.7073.; Language note: French (Box-folder 44/1)
      - Introduction et allegro. Paris: A. Durand, 1906., Arranged by the composer for two pianos; score; 25 p.; Plate no. D. & F.6811. (Box-folder 44/2)
      - Introduction et allegro. Paris: A. Durand, 1906., Solo harp part only; score; 13 p.; Plate no. D. & F.6738. (Box-folder 44/3)
      - Ma mère l'oye. Paris: A. Durand, 1910., Piano, four hands; score; 31 p.; Plate no. D. & F.7746. (Box-folder 44/4)
      - Ma mère l'oye. Paris: A. Durand, 1912., Solo piano; score; 44 p.; Plate no. D. & F.8395. (Box-folder 44/5)
      - Menuet antique. Paris: Enoch, 1898., Solo piano; score; 8 p.; Plate no. E. & C.3616. (Box-folder 44/6)
      - Rapsodie espagnole. Paris: A. Durand, 1908., Reduction for piano, four hands; score; 32 p.; Plate no. D. & F.6999.; BOX: 44/8 Copy 2 of the above. (Box-folder 44/7-8)
      - Shéhérazade. Paris: A. Durand, 1911., Piano-vocal score; 24 p.; Plate no. D. & F.7993.; Published 1911/1912; Language note: French; Language note: English (Box-folder 44/9)
      - Trio pour piano, violon et violoncelle. Paris: A. Durand, 1915., Piano score, parts; 35 p.; 11 p.; 12 p.; Plate no. D. & F.9346. (Box-folder 44/10)
    - Rechkunov, M.
      - Requiem. Moscow: Gosudarstvennoe izdatel'stvo, Muzykal'nyĭ sektor, 1928., Voice and piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. M.8397 G.; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 44/11)
    - Respighi, Ottorino
      - Antiche danze ed arie [per liuto], v. 1. Milan: G. Ricordi, 1919., Arranged for solo piano; score; 21 p.; Plate no. 117515. (Box-folder 44/12)
      - Antiche danze ed arie [per liuto], v. 2. Milan: G. Ricordi, 1924., Arranged for piano, four hands.; 37 p.; Plate no. 119578. (Box-folder 44/13)
      - La boutique fantasque See: Rossini, Gioacchino
    - Ricci, Luigi and Federico Ricci
      - Crispino e la comare. Milan: G. Ricordi, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 242 p.; Plate no. 42055.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 45/1)
    - Rimskiĭ-Korsakov, Nikolaĭ Andreevich
      - Antar, op. 9. Paris: A. Leduc, 1911., Solo piano; score; 39 p.; Plate no. A.L.14729. (Box-folder 45/2)
      - Capriccio espagnol, op. 34. Leipzig: M.P. Belaïeff, 1887., Arranged by the composer for piano, four hands; score; 39 p.; Plate no. 99. (Box-folder 45/3)
      - Le coq d'or. [=Zolotoĭ pietushok.] Moscow: P. Jurgenson, 1896., Piano-vocal score; 206 p.; Plate no. 32405.; Published 1896/1907; Contains autograph of Lifar on inside front cover, in ink, dated 1914; score contains substantial annotations in pencil.; Language note: French; Language note: Russian (Box-folder S/52)
      - Le coq d'or: Suite. [=Four musical pictures.] Moscow: P. Jurgenson, n.d., Full score; 106 p.; Plate no. 33585. (Box-folder 45/4)
      - Le coq d'or: Suite. Moscow: P. Jurgenson, n.d., Arranged by K. Chernov for piano, four hands; score; 61 p.; Plate no. 34239. (Box-folder 45/5)
      - Fantaziia na serbskiia temy, op. 6. [=Fantasia on Serbian themes.] Leipzig: M.P. Belaïeff, 1895., Arranged by the composer for piano, four hands; score; 23 p.; Plate no. 1054. (Box-folder 45/6)
      - Maĭskaia noch': Ukraĭnskaia noch' i pesny Levki (Act III). [=May night: Ukranian night and Levka's song.] Leipzig: M.P. Belaïeff, 1895., Piano-vocal score; 9 p.; Plate no. 979.1126.; incomplete after p. 9; Language note: French; Language note: German; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 45/7)
      - [Mozart and Salieri.] [S.l.]: [s.n.], n.d., Piano-vocal score; [15] p.; Plate no. 1617.; incomplete: p. 37 through 53 (end of opera) only; Language note: German; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 45/8)
      - Noch' pered Rozhdestvom. [=La nuit de Noël; Christmas eve.] Leipzig: M.P. Belaïeff, 1895., Piano-vocal score; 292 p.; Plate no. 1091.; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 45/9)
      - Pskovitianka. St. Petersburg: V. Bessel', 1894., Piano-vocal score; 205 p.; Plate no. 3773 through 3789.; Contains annotations in pencil and in ink.; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 46/1)